

Beiyu.Hu@mail.polimi.it

Linkedin:

(+39) 3899 137638, (+86) 135 3761 5137

linkedin.com/in/beiyuhu/



INTRODUCTION

LEED AP (BD+C) since 2020, 4-years experience in building environment industry. Currently a master student in Building and Architectural Engineering of Politecnico di Milano.

Familiar with and passionate in parametric computational design, sustainable building, building performance analysis (thermal, visual), energy efficiency analysis, CFD airflow assessment, data post-process and visualization.

Fast self-learning skill, high stress resistance.

SKILL + SOFTWARE

Thermal comfort & Energy modeling

**** **** + IES - Virtual Environment (Apache, ApacheHVAC)

+ Grasshopper - Honeybee (Energy+, OpenStudio)

+ TRNsys - SketchUp

Visual comfort & Daylight

**** **** + IES - Virtual Environment (FlucsDL)

+ Grasshopper - Honeybee, HB[+] (Radiance, Daysim)

Computational Fluid Dynamics

+ IES - Virtual Environment (marcoFlo, microFlo)

+ Grasshopper - Butterfly (OpenFOAM)

Data post-process and visualization

+ Excel (vlookup/match/index/ifs)

+ Python (matplotlib, bokeh)

+ MATLAB (basic equation solution)

Otherwards:

**** **** + AutoCAD: 6-years experience

+ Adobe suite (PS, AI, ID)

**** + Climate consultant, LBNL THERM, WINDOW

EXTRACURRICULAR TRAINING

'Environmental Artificial Intelligencel in Design' by DigitalFutures 07/2021

04/2021 'Introduction to C.S and Programming Using Python' by MITx

LUIICYTIUM

	EDUCATION					
Since 02/2020	MSc Building and Architectural Engineering (BE track)		Politecnico di Milano, Italy	(27.3 /30, 91/100)		
	 + Building Energy Modeling + Lab + Energy Efficient Buildings + Design Optioneering + Fundamental of Integrated Building Design + Adaptive Facade Studio + Building Service + BS Energy Modeling Lab 	(30/30): (30/30): (30/30): (28/30):	Passive house strategies and Optimize net Zero-Energy Bu Parametric desgin optimization Sustainable building study Visual and Thermal comfort of Solar thermal/electric, Heat p	uilding on evaluation		
09/2011 - 06/2015	BEng Building Environment and Equipment (HVA	AC track)	Guangzhou University, China	(3.6/4.0)		
	+ Building Indoor Environment / Heat pump / Heating Ventilation and Air Conditioning					
	PROJECT EXPERIENCE					
02/2021 - 06/2021	CasAselvino energy efficient optimization as Energy modeler					
	+ Massing & passive strategies optimization, Energy & thermal comfort assessment, Data post-processing					
02/2021 - 06/2021	'Begonia' Responsive Facade in Shenzhen as Team leader, Environmental designer					
	+ Parametric design, Visual comfort (daylight) and Thermal comfort (energy) evaluation, Iterative optimization					
09/2020 - 12/2020	Environment Based Pavilion in Shenzhen	ment Based Pavilion in Shenzhen as Environmental designer				
	+ Outdoor airflow(CFD) analysis, Solar radiation analysis					
09/2020 - 02/2021	Marcello Primary School Retrofit in Milano	as Team leader, Energy modeler				
	 Climate analysis, Envelope (opaque and glazing) improvement, Passive strategies: shadings + natural ventilation Energy simulation, Thermal loads, Thermal comfort assessment, Data post-processing and visualization 					
08/2014 - 10/2014	Research of Condensation Heat Recovery for Outdoor Environment as Team leader					
	+ On-site collection of AC device heat extraction parameter, in-lab experimental verification					
	WORK EXPERIENCE					
04/2017 - 01/2020	PT Architecture Design (Shenzhen) Co., Ltd	as Building S	Service Engineer			

+ Assist and coordinate architects and civil engineers from schematic stage

+ Technical drawings: HVAC end system, MEP service room

Project: HaiNan International Exhibition Center, Sino-Japanese Hotel, ShenZhen Mixc mall retrofit

03/2015 - 04/2017

WSP (Parsons Brinckerhoff) | Guangzhou Office as Building Service Engineer

+ Assist and coordinate architects and civil engineers, Building energy modeling, thermal load calculation

+ Schematic drawings: Central cooling system, Service room

Project: HeFei Evergrande Office Center, GuangZhou Infinitus Plaza, GuangZhou Everbright mansion.

胡钡雨

E-mail: Beiyu.Hu@mail.polimi.it

Phone: (+39) 3899 137638, (+86) 135 3761 5137

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/beiyuhu/



INTRODUCTION

持有 LEED AP (BD+C) 及助理工程师, 4年多建筑环境范畴工作经验。 计划 2022 从米兰理工大学建筑与建造工程专业硕士研究生毕业,研究课题与数据驱动参数化建筑能耗预测相关。

熟悉 参数化计算机设计,可持续建筑,建筑表现分析(热环境与光环境),建筑能效分析, CFD 气流组织模拟, 数据后处理与可视化, 且对其有浓厚兴趣。

自学能力强, 抗高压能力强。

SKILL + SOFTWARE

热舒适 & 能耗模拟

+ IES - Virtual Environment (Apache, ApacheHVAC)

+ Grasshopper - Honeybee (Energy+, OpenStudio)

+ TRNsys - SketchUp

视觉舒适 & 日照分析

**** + IES - Virtual Environment (FlucsDL)

+ Grasshopper - Honeybee, HB[+] (Radiance, Daysim)

计算流体力学 (气流组织模拟)

+ IES - Virtual Environment (marcoFlo, microFlo)

+ Grasshopper - Butterfly (OpenFOAM)

数据后处理 & 可视化

+ Excel (vlookup/match/index/ifs)

 \star \star \star + Python (matplotlib, bokeh)

+ MATLAB (basic equation solution)

其他

. . . .

**** + AutoCAD

+ Adobe suite (PS, AI, ID)

**** + Climate consultant, LBNL THERM, WINDOW

EXTRACURRICULAR TRAINING

07/2021 '设计中的环境智能' by DigitalFutures

03/2020 'Introduction to C.S and Programming Using Python' by MITx

	EDUCATION				
Since 02/2020	nce 02/2020 硕士 建筑与建造工程 (Building Engineering track)		型工大学 (27.3/30), 90.1/100)	
	 + Building Energy Modeling + Lab + Design Optioneering + Fundamental of Integrated Building Design 	(29/30): 被动豆(30/30): 计算额(30/30): 整体额(28/30): 自适应	参数化设计 及 优化 建筑 及 可持续建筑分 立动态幕墙的热环境与	能效模拟 析 形环境分析	
09/2011 - 06/2015	学士 建筑环境与设备工程 (暖通空调方向)	ナかけ	(3.6/4.0)		
	PROJECT EXPERIENCE				
02/2021 - 06/2021	CasAselvino 装配式建筑能效分析	as 能耗模拟工程	到师		
	+ 墙体热质、遮阳通风优化,空气及地源热交	唤、 <i>太阳能优化,</i>	热舒适及能效评估,	数据后处理及可视化	
02/2021 - 06/2021	'海棠式'自适应幕墙分析优化	as 负责人 + 环	竟模拟工程师		
	+ 参数化几何设计,视觉舒适(日照)及热舒适(能耗)评估,设计探索及迭代优化				
09/2020 - 12/2020	基于室外风环境及太阳辐射优化的参数化亭	as 环境模拟工程	即		

+ 室外气流组织及太阳辐射模拟及优化

09/2020 - 02/2021

米兰 Marcello 小学可持续建筑旧改项目

as 负责人 + 能耗模拟工程师

+ 气象参数分析,幕墙(窗+墙)性能提升及保温,被动式策略:遮阳研究及自然通风优化

+ 能耗模拟,热舒适模型评估,冷热负荷计算,数据后处理及可视化

08/2014 - 10/2014

室外热环境空调室外机冷凝热回收研究项目 as 负责人

+ 挑战杯校赛三等奖;室外现场调研,实验室热回收实验验证

WORK EXPERIENCE

04/2017 - 01/2020 深圳柏涛蓝森国际建筑设计有限公司

as 暖通工程师

+ 涉及方案、初设、施工图阶段,制定暖通方案并配合建筑及结构布置机房管井

+ 计算负荷、风量等并完成计算书,绘制系统、末端、机房等工程图纸,驻场协调项目:海南国际会展中心二期,长春中日友好酒店,深圳罗湖万象城改造

03/2015 - 04/2017

WSP (Parsons Brinckerhoff) 科进 (柏诚) | 广州 as 暖通工程师

+ 涉及方案、初设阶段,协助总工完成项目负荷计算,国内外标准研究

+ 绘制初设平面及系统图,方案与建筑单位配合

项目: 合肥恒大中心塔楼,广州无限极广场,广州光大大厦